has had leadership roles in numerous
indian organizations and activities
including
serving as chairman of the federation of
india community associations the fica
and we are humbled by your contributions
thank you let's give them a big hand
[Applause]
it is my high honor
and distinct privilege to stand here
today
to introduce
ramesha
my friend
to the international hall of fame in
once said
if you want to find god
you must lose yourself in the service of
others
ramesh bhai or brother ramesh
as he is affectionately called
has been living this adage
through the work of medical yatra
or medical pilgrimage
millions of our fellow human beings
are born
and die
without ever
seeing a doctor
even today
good and confident medical care
is a province
of the habs
rameshwai
by taking medical yakra to rural parts
of india
has worked
to redress
this imbalance
starting in the year 2001
working with his illustrious wife
jayavin shah
rameshwai
envisioned this project
and have taken
fica
and
[Applause]
american association of
asian indian physicians
10 000 miles away to the streets of
rural india
helping six to eight thousand people
every year
today medical yatra
has a early cancer detection mobile van
that goes from village to village
and provides this service
because as we know
early detection
is the best detection
in the history of cleveland
international hall of fame
mr ramiksha enjoys a unique distinction
he will be the part of the first ever
husband and wife team
to be part of the cleveland
international hall of fame
[Music]
so with pride and joy
of the indian american community of
northeast ohio
i hereby induct
mr ramesh shah into the cleveland
international hall of fame
[Applause]
uh
thank you very much
for destroying this honor to me
at cleveland international
but to be very honest with you
this honor
belongs to a lot of people
that i'm going to mention
the physicians
of the ethno community
and now in the united states will come
individually
about 300 physicians and volunteers
about 300 financial supporters
30 rotary clubs
in india
and 10 rotary club in united states and
then
and my family
especially sadly
with four grandchildren
who
stopped their mother
and lived full to stand
on donation letters
and then in david hansen
who maintained
our website medical yatra
growing up
in a small town
of 10 thousand people
by the way is not on the map
my greatest ambition
for to see
the bollywood movies
in a diamond city surah
[Music]
year 1991
the very first
medical mission
done by business international
from lawrence ohio
to build a church
in larado mexico
depart the first day
my wife jaya
started seeing the children
start providing
pediatric services
and everybody was busy
so i asked
norman
what i am supposed to do
for five years
so he can be
pair of scissors
and they call
normally
to cut the air
of this mexican children
and wash them and give them sour
and make them a million-dollar man so
this is my first job
as a medical minister
the first important lesson i learned
the humidity
is the key
ingredient
in medical volunteer missions
all our physicians will come to yachts
in india
have
one surprise
pick up the medical
medicine boxes
take up the room
and clean the
clinical site
and sometimes tolerant
very dirty
toilets
in the villages
i'm very very proud of
our medieval community of medical yoga
year 2009
after about 10 years in medical
healthcare
by accident
i was invited
to attend
the meeting of mary
totally evening by chinese
and they were again
and then changed the complete profile of
medical lab
they taught me how to do the global
grants
of
totally international
we have done
15 rotary grants in last 10 years
invested one and a half
million dollars
in various sustainable projects
[Applause]
village
or
cancer
cervical cancer clinics
and
selling the repair message
our connection with the rotary
have changed complete perspective
about the health situation in india
medical
data success
sold into rotary clubs
and rotary international
because of pottery
they are connected
not
on the early days
on weekly basis and sometimes daily
basis
medical life has become
daily behavior
and has become more innovative
in conclusion
i want to say with you the quote
from dr patricia gordon
harvard md
oncologist
cnn eu
2021 doctor practice according to cnn
hero
and i quote
i have learned
that high-tech solutions
are not necessarily
the best way to solve medical problems
in the low
income
low this is third world countries
often
simple solutions
such as cryotherapy
cryotherapy
no anesthesia
no hospitalization
for
many pre-medical
reasons
shown more beautifully
and more efficient
i learned a lot of things from dr said
thank you again all of you
to listen to the story
of hairstylist
certified in mexico
to be a
hall of famer today
[Applause]
you